<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work Portfolio: David Stainton</title>
    <link>https://sphinx.rs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Work Portfolio: David Stainton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sphinx.rs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cryptocomrade: Cryptography in Golang</title>
      <link>https://sphinx.rs/blog/golang_cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sphinx.rs/blog/golang_cryptography/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I will share with you how I write cryptography software in Go. I won&amp;rsquo;t be discussing TLS here at all except to say that the only acceptable use for TLS is to talk to legacy systems such as &amp;ldquo;the web&amp;rdquo;. If you are building something new then the Noise Protocol Framework is a much better choice.
This is a work in progress. I&amp;rsquo;ll periodically update this so as to fix mistakes and add more content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://sphinx.rs/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sphinx.rs/contact/</guid>
      <description> Email: dstainton415@gmail.com   Social  Twitter linkedin github  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Stainton&#39;s Mentorships</title>
      <link>https://sphinx.rs/mentorships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sphinx.rs/mentorships/</guid>
      <description>Mentorships   In 2017 I mentored Katharina Kohls from Bochum University (Germany) in the use of Tor and txtorcon to make customized Tor circuits for her Tor research project. Katharina&amp;rsquo;s work can be found here: https://www.infsec.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/lehrstuhl/mitarbeiter/kohls/
  In 2020 I mentored Denis Varlakov from Tomsk State University (Siberia) in writing a comprehensive TCP injection detector which was directly inspired by my work on Honeybadger. Denis&amp;rsquo;s software is written in Rust and can be found here: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Stainton&#39;s Open Source Projects</title>
      <link>https://sphinx.rs/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sphinx.rs/projects/</guid>
      <description>See David Stainton&amp;rsquo;s github profile for additional open source projects.
Rust I learned Rust by writing cryptography libraries and solving cryptopals challenges.
 My solutions to some of the cryptopals challenges  So firstly, let me just state that I didn&amp;rsquo;t solve all of the challenges yet. I did most of the first two sets. My process for learning Rust at the same time was to first solve the challenge in Golang and then port my solution to Rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Stainton&#39;s technical writing</title>
      <link>https://sphinx.rs/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sphinx.rs/writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing   My Google Scholar Profile
  Least Authority&amp;rsquo;s Blog: Introduction to Mix Networks and Anonymous Communication Networks
  LeastAuthority TFA GmbH published this blog post I wrote as an introduction to mix networks and anonymous communication.
 Katzenpost Mix Network Design Specifications  These Katzenpost mix network design specification documents are the direct result of a three month collaboration with Yawning Angel, George Danezis, Claudia Diaz, Ania Piotrowska and myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://sphinx.rs/publicspeaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sphinx.rs/publicspeaking/</guid>
      <description>These talks primarily took place in various areas of Europe where I talked about mix networks, a kind of anonymous communication network.
My goal in these talks was to make some complex topics understandable to a non-technical audience and to advocate for privacy enhancing technology, especially anonymous communication networks. I believe that people&amp;rsquo;s untrained mathematical intuition is enough of a prerequisite for understanding deeply technical and complex topics involving cryptography and probability theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
